weddingforward.com 2018-09-30

# Privacy Policy | Wedding Forward

If you require any more information or have any questions about our privacy policy, please feel free to contact us by email at support@weddingforward.com.

At www.weddingforward.com, the privacy of our visitors is of extreme importance to us. This privacy policy document outlines the types of personal information is received and collected by www.weddingforward.com and how it is used.

## This policy is incorporated to the Service’s iOS App Terms of Service and Extend App Terms of Service.

WEDDINGFORWARD.COM complies with the U.S. – Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of personal data from Canada. WEDDINGFORWARD.COM has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement.

## What personally identifiable information do you have to provide WEDDINGFORWARD.COM?

When you register for any Services or contact us, you may be asked to provide WEDDINGFORWARD.COM an active e-mail address, name, and to select a password. Registration with the Services is free of charge.

When you use our Services, we automatically collect information on the type of device you use, operating system version, mobile carrier and device identifier. We collect this information for the purpose of optimizing your use of our applications.

Please bear in mind that false, incorrect, or outdated information may prevent you from registering or impair WEDDINGFORWARD.COM’s ability to provide you with the Services and to contact you.

## What Internet traffic does WEDDINGFORWARD.COM collect?

To benefit from the Services and depending on the products you use, your access to the Internet through your mobile phone may be routed through WEDDINGFORWARD.COM’s servers, which strive to reduce the volume of your downloads, and potentially your uploads as well. We may also collect information regarding your usage of applications and the consumption of data by such applications in order to provide you with detailed information with respect to the data consumption of applications that you use, and recommendations how to decrease such consumption.

When you use the Services and depending on the product you use, WEDDINGFORWARD.COM may collect information, such as session durations, page impressions, details of your mobile operator, Internet protocol (IP) addresses, the domain name that served you to access the Services, and content types and origins.

WEDDINGFORWARD.COM may also store information related to online data or metadata that is routed through WEDDINGFORWARD.COM’s servers, such as webpages’ addresses, structures, data fields, and images. However, WEDDINGFORWARD.COM will not store any content that you upload or download, such as message text, filled-in forms, and data that a website retrieved.

The stored data will be attributed to you in person, only to the extent necessary to provide you the Services, as set in the following chapter. Thereafter, WEDDINGFORWARD.COM will anonymize the data and will not knowingly use the data to personally identify you.

Further information may be collected when you and WEDDINGFORWARD.COM exchange communications, for example, when you submit an inquiry to the Service’s customer support at: support@weddingforward.com

## Does WEDDINGFORWARD.COM collect location based information?

WEDDINGFORWARD.COM does not actively collect any personal information that is based on your geographical location, except for the country/city that you reside in when accessing the Services (if applicable), including when the Services are not activated, for example to detect that you are abroad and offer you to activate the Services. However, certain location based information may be stored on WEDDINGFORWARD.COM’s servers, for example if you use the Services to access geographic based services. WEDDINGFORWARD.COM will use such information subject to this policy and will anonymize such data as soon as it is no longer necessary for providing you the Services. We also collect your geo-location information for the purpose of monetizing your phone usage for roaming users. If you no longer wish to allow us to use this information you may turn this off at the device level or deactivate your account. Please note that if you turn off this feature some parts of our service may not work.

## What does WEDDINGFORWARD.COM do with your personally identifiable information?

WEDDINGFORWARD.COM may use personally identifiable information for the following purposes:

To provide and operate the Services; For example, to provide you with information on the extent of saved data volume, to provide you with support, to help you better understand your Internet use habits and accordingly increase the efficiency of the Services for you. WEDDINGFORWARD.COM will retain such data in a manner that is attributable to you for a period of 12 months and will anonymize the data thereafter. WEDDINGFORWARD.COM may keep aggregated usage data in a manner attributable to you for as long as required.

If WEDDINGFORWARD.COM decides to offer certain Services for a fee, then certain payment and transactions related information will be stored and used. Such data will remain personally identifiable for as long as necessary to provide you the fee-based Services, and any other purpose related to your use of such Services;

To send you updates and notices and to provide you with information related to the Services; WEDDINGFORWARD.COM will not share your e-mail address or any other personally identifiable information with WEDDINGFORWARD advertisers and advertising networks, without your explicit consent

To enforce the Master Subscription Agreement;

To contact you as and when WEDDINGFORWARD.COM believes it to be necessary;

To comply with any applicable law and assist law enforcement agencies as required, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process, when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request;

In any case where WEDDINGFORWARD.COM believes that the use of the information is necessary to prevent imminent physical harm or damage to property;

To collect fees and debts, and to prevent fraud, misappropriation, infringements, identity thefts and any other misuse of the Services;

To take any action in any case of dispute, or legal proceeding of any kind between you and WEDDINGFORWARD.COM, or between you and other users or third parties with respect to, or in relation with the Services

## Push Notifications

We send you push notifications to your mobile device in order to send you updates about the application, content, products, application usage and other important details about your use of the application. If you no longer wish to receive these types of communications you may opt-out at the device level.

## Important notice about children’s privacy

The Services are not intended for use by persons under the age of 13. If you are not 13 years old or older, then you may not use any of the Services and must not provide any of your personal details. We do not knowingly collect personal information from users under the age of 13.

## How does WEDDINGFORWARD.COM Share your personally identifiable information with others?

WEDDINGFORWARD.COM does not sell, rent or lease your personally identifiable information to third parties. WEDDINGFORWARD.COM may share personally identifiable information with others in any of the following instances, or subject to your explicit consent:

To operate the Services, including to store and process your information through a third party hosting services;

To contact you. For example, WEDDINGFORWARD.COM may use a third party’s mailing platform to send you messages and updates from time to time;

If WEDDINGFORWARD.COM believes that you have breached the Master Subscription Agreement, or abused your rights to use the Services, or performed any act or omission that WEDDINGFORWARD.COM believes to be violating any applicable law, rules, or regulations. WEDDINGFORWARD.COM may share your information with law enforcement agencies and other competent authorities as well as with other third parties, as may be required;

If WEDDINGFORWARD.COM is required, or believes that it is required by law to share or disclose your information;

In any case of dispute, or legal proceeding of any kind between you and WEDDINGFORWARD.COM, or between you and other users or third parties with respect to, or in relation with the Services;

In any case where WEDDINGFORWARD.COM believes that sharing information is necessary to prevent imminent physical harm or damage to property;

If WEDDINGFORWARD.COM is involved in a merger or acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information;

WEDDINGFORWARD.COM may also share personally identifiable information with companies or organizations connected, or affiliated with WEDDINGFORWARD.COM, such as subsidiaries, sister-companies and parent companies.

## How does WEDDINGFORWARD.COM use aggregated information?

WEDDINGFORWARD.COM may also use anonymous, statistical or aggregated information to properly operate the Services, to improve the quality and functionality of the Services, to enhance your experience, to create new services, including customized services, to change or cancel existing content or services and for other internal and statistical purposes.

WEDDINGFORWARD.COM may share, sell, publish, post, disseminate, transmit or otherwise communicate or make available such information, to suppliers, business partners, sponsors, affiliates and any other third party, at WEDDINGFORWARD.COM’s sole discretion, provided however, that WEDDINGFORWARD.COM will not knowingly, or intentionally use the information to reveal your identity without your consent.

## How can you access your personal information?

If you are registered with the Services, then you may access your personal account and edit or amend your personal information at any time by contacting us at support@weddingforward.com. If you find that the information on your personal account is not accurate, complete, you wish to delete inaccuracies or update it, than you may request that we make all necessary changes to correct it. We will respond to your access request within 30 days.

We will retain your information (including geo-location data) for as long as any of your registered accounts are active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at support@weddingforward.com. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

## What opt-out and deletion options are available to you?

At any time you may opt out of WEDDINGFORWARD.COM’s services, by sending WEDDINGFORWARD.COM a removal request to: support@weddingforward.com. It may take up to Thirty (30) business days for your opt-out request to take effect.

If you wish to delete your personally identifiable information that is stored in WEDDINGFORWARD.COM’s database, you may send a request to delete information to: support@weddingforward.com. WEDDINGFORWARD.COM will inform you whether it can accept your request. WEDDINGFORWARD.COM may refuse your request, for example, if WEDDINGFORWARD.COM believes that removal of certain information may jeopardize certain activities of the Services, or harm other users. In any case, WEDDINGFORWARD.COM may keep any aggregated or anonymized information for statistical, marketing and other purposes, indefinitely.

## How does WEDDINGFORWARD.COM secure your personal Information?

WEDDINGFORWARD.COM and third parties on its behalf implement information security systems and procedures to secure your personal information. While such systems and procedures reduce the risk of security breaches, they do not provide absolute security. Therefore, WEDDINGFORWARD.COM cannot guarantee that the Services will be immune from any wrongdoings, malfunctions, unlawful interceptions or unauthorized access to the information stored therein and to other information security risks, or that your private communications on or through the Services will remain private. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

We restrict access to personal information you provided WEDDINGFORWARD.COM to our employees, contractors, vendors and agents who need to know that information for the purposes described in this policy. These individuals are obligated to keep your personal information confidential and they may be subject to penalties, termination of relations and criminal prosecution, if they fail to comply with such obligations.

When we collect sensitive information (such as geo-location data) within our mobile applications, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

## How does WEDDINGFORWARD.COM use cookies?

WEDDINGFORWARD.COM may use cookies when operating the Services. Cookies are packets of information sent by WEDDINGFORWARD.COM’s servers to your web browser and then sent back by the browser. WEDDINGFORWARD.COM may use cookies for various purposes, for example, to save you the need to re-enter your password each time you log-in to the Services, to facilitate the use of the Services, to collect information for statistical and analytical purposes, to verify information, to customize the Services to your personal preferences and for information security purposes. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personal information you submit while on our site.

Some of the cookies may expire when the session ends and you exit your browser. Other cookies may be stored on your computer’s hard drive. If you wish to block the cookies, then please use the help button in your browser and follow the necessary instructions. However, bear in mind that disabling cookies may complicate or even prevent your use of the Services, or certain features thereof.

The use of third party cookies is not covered by our privacy policy. We do not have access or control over these cookies.

## Web Beacons and Web Bugs

Our third party tracking utility partner employs a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers’ personally identifiable information.

## Mobile Analytics

We use mobile analytics software to allow us to better understand the functionality of our Service on your phone. This software may record information such as how often you use the application, the events that occur within the application, aggregated usage, performance data, and where the application was downloaded from. We do not link the information we store within the analytics software to any personally identifiable information you submit within the mobile app.

## Where is my personal information processed?

WEDDINGFORWARD.COM stores and processes the information through a third party’s hosting services. If you are in the European Economic Area, or in any other jurisdiction that regulates the transfer of personal information outside that jurisdiction, then you hereby grant WEDDINGFORWARD.COM your explicit and unambiguous consent to transfer your personal information, for the purposes described in this policy.

## Links to Third Party sites or apps

Our Web site and mobile applications contains links to other sites or mobile applications that are not owned or controlled by us. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites or applications.

We encourage you to be aware that when you leave our site or mobile applications and to read the privacy policies of each and every Web site and mobile application that collects personal information.

This privacy policy applies only to information collected by our Web site or mobile applications.

## Enforcement

WEDDINGFORWARD.COM is doing its utmost to comply with this Policy. If you have any questions, concerns or complaints regarding this policy and the enforcement thereof, please refer them to: support@weddingforward.com. After receiving your complaint, WEDDINGFORWARD.COM may contact you to better understand your concerns and will make all efforts to promptly answer your question, or resolve your complaint to your full satisfaction.

## Social Media (Features) and Widgets

Our Services includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button [and Widgets, such as the Share this button, Pin button, etc]. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

WEDDINGFORWARD.COM may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

## DoubleClick DART Cookie

.:: Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on www.weddingforward.com.

.:: Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to www.weddingforward.com and other sites on the Internet.

.:: Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL – http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html

Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our advertising partners include ….

Google Adsense

Google DoubleClick

Commission Junction

Affiliate Window

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on www.weddingforward.com send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies ( such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons ) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

www.weddingforward.com has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. www.weddingforward.com’s privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites.

**Last Updated: March 4, 2016**
